<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1250"?><doc>    <defaults>        <defaultpage datatype="core" friendlyname="">index</defaultpage>        <layoutpage datatype="core" friendlyname=""></layoutpage>        <owner datatype="core" friendlyname="">clement</owner></defaults>    <metadata>        <navorder>0</navorder>        <pagetitle datatype="property" friendlyname="Page title">Reviews</pagetitle>        <linktext datatype="property" friendlyname="Page linktext">Reviews</linktext>        <keywords datatype="property" friendlyname="Keyword list">Reviews of Jewitt music</keywords>        <description datatype="property" friendlyname="Page description">Reviews</description>        <author datatype="property" friendlyname="Page author">clement</author></metadata>    <content>        <content1 datatype="string" friendlyname="LH heading 1">{CMS_CONTENT1}</content1>        <content2 datatype="text" friendlyname="Content"><p>This page contains extracts from what others thought: endorsements, reviews and other comments on my work.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>GENERAL COMMENTS<br /></h2>
<p><cite>From <strong><a href="http://www.rodpaton.com" target="_blank">Dr Rod Paton</a></strong>, University of Chichester, England</cite>. "... a fertile imagination, a high level of musical understanding and an exacting attention  to details of technique ...&nbsp; modernist but entirely accessible ... a deep sense of engagement with performer and  potential audience ... engaged with a 'new paradigm' of aesthetics which places creative  process at the heart of psychic development."</p>
<p><cite>From <strong><a href="http://www.ump.co.uk/composer%20pages/burrell.htm" target="_blank">Diana Burrell</a></strong>, Guildhall School of Music and Drama, London.</cite> "Clement is a fine musician with far-reaching interests and a wide experience of all kinds of music-making.  &hellip; each  new work shows an ever-increasing sophistication in scope, form, instrumental colouring, etc."</p>
<p><cite>from <strong><a title="about us" href="http://members.ozemail.com.au/~docsyd/index.html" target="_blank">Dr Sydney Baggs</a></strong>, New South Wales, Australia</cite> <br />"Your music is evocative and haunting.  It has a mysterious quality that is very appealing."</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>ON SPECIFIC COMPOSITIONS / PERFORMANCES</h2>
<h3><em><strong>The Night Sea: aspects of an ordinary life<br /></strong></em></h3>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em></em>(Walt Whitman, Richard Eberhart, Charles Wright, bell hooks, Connie  Bensley, the composer, Mark Strand &amp; e.e.cummings) 2003-5, for solo female vocalist, male voice choir and 19  instrumentalists; duration c.50&rsquo;.</p>
<p><cite>From <a href="http://www.vivosvoco.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Jonathan Harvey</strong></a>.</cite>&nbsp; It's a powerful piece, I would love to hear it ... as a marriage of music and textual journey it must be quite an  experience ... I was impressed by the economy and directness of the writing ... a strong musico&ndash;ritualistic expression ... the movements are all quite terse without being mean;  they have some generosity of expansion as well.  The canonic stuff also strikes me as very beautifully calculated. &hellip; an inventiveness of imagination in the ... distinctive overall quality of the song's dominant material. &hellip; created with a powerful  imagination.</p>
<p><cite>From <strong>Diana Burrell.&nbsp; </strong></cite>This is a rich, colourful work, brimfull of life and energy! ... goes right to the heart of creation, celebrating  humankind's place in the cosmos ...&nbsp; here is one [score] I'd really like to hear, for in an  age addicted to irony and superficiality, this is a strong, generous piece of music which truly deserves a  performance.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><strong><em>Invocations to Archangels </em></strong></h3>
<p>(composer&rsquo;s text) 2002.  Counter-tenor, 2 tenors, baritone   Duration c.8&rsquo;.  Choral  version, SATB, 2003.</p>
<p><strong>Pers. comms from listeners to the quartet version.&nbsp; </strong></p>
<p><strong>"</strong>The music is evocative and haunting.  The sounds recalled me to a symphony of souls I heard while in an altered  state."  <a href="http://www.kabbalahofprayer.com/about-shulamit-soulsongs.html" target="_blank"><strong><em>Shulamit Elson</em></strong></a>, author of Kabbalah of Prayer: sacred sounds and the soul&rsquo;s journey.</p>
<p>"I chanced (?) to switch on the radio this morning ... and at once found myself listening utterly  spellbound to something profoundly beautiful.  &hellip; this hauntingly beautiful mysterious sound."&nbsp; <cite>Acquaintance <strong>Sue Thoma</strong>.</cite></p>
<p><strong>On the choral version.</strong></p>
<p><a name="anchor01"></a><strong>Leicester Mercury</strong> 6th November 2008: "... The choir ... [gave] stunning performances of 20th Century music in the second half.&nbsp; Clement Jewitt's Invocations to Archangels ... the more I listened, the more its calming, mesmerizing qualities became apparent." <em><strong>Peter Collett</strong></em>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><em><strong>&ldquo;But we must still be seeking?&rdquo;</strong></em></h3>
<p>2001.  Wind quintet, duration 15&rsquo;.  Winner of Birmingham Chamber Music Society  prize.</p>
<p><strong>Tempo</strong> No.220, April 2002, p.40<em><strong></strong></em>: &hellip;  One might be forgiven for thinking that a new wind quintet in a programme that also included works for the medium  by Hindemith, Ligeti, Nielsen and Jan&aacute;cek would be lost, but it says a lot for Jewitt&rsquo;s piece that this was not  the case ... an undeniably effective  work. &hellip;  from simple  beginnings the language is modified and expanded, often very lyrically but also contrapuntally, to take account  of the new dialectics that are being formed.  ". <em><strong>Raymond Head</strong></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><em><strong>Chechnya Story</strong></em></h3>
<p>(after a text by Olivia Ward, award winning reporter for the Toronto Star) 1997.   2 narrators,  trombone, 2 percussion, strings 4 2 2 1; duration 32&rsquo;.</p>
<p><strong>Coventry Evening Telegraph </strong>27th March 1998<em></em>. &hellip; most striking &hellip; melodrama, but any association of Jewitt&rsquo;s sensitive expressions with that over-used term with  its meaning today is wildly inappropriate &hellip; an  overwhelming statement of compassion.  Words set by composers like Schubert and Bach become transfigured by the  process of being adorned with music, and for one of those rare times in my life, I felt that such comparisons are  anything but ridiculous.<strong> </strong><em><strong>Stephen Daw</strong>.</em></p>
<p><strong>Toronto Star </strong>14th March 2000<strong>.</strong><em></em> &hellip; left a Canada House audience haunted &hellip; brooding score &hellip; formed a harrowing  backdrop to the spoken word delivery of Ward&rsquo;s text.<strong> </strong><em><strong>Mitch Potter</strong>.</em></p>
<p><strong>Pers. Comm. </strong>&hellip; I look back to the Chechnya piece as one of the most interesting and stimulating pieces in which I was  privileged to be involved and thank you sincerely for that memory. <strong><em>Corinne Lang</em></strong> (narrator).</p>
<p><strong>Vivian Ellis Prize Reader </strong>1998.  A powerful thought provoking epic dramatic score. It would work well as a dance piece or even film score, but not as a musical in its present form. [Well, that submission was just curiosity - I knew full well it was not what they were looking for!]</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><em><strong>Knit Up the Ravell&rsquo;d Sleeve of Care</strong></em></h3>
<p>1995-6.  11 bassoons, 1 contra-bassoon.  Duration c.15&rsquo;.</p>
<p><strong>Birmingham Post </strong>18th May 1996<strong>.</strong><em></em> &hellip; substantial and darkly atmospheric as various combinations emerge both physically and musically from the  pools of the unconscious mind.<strong> </strong><em><strong>Christopher Morley</strong>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></content2>        <content3 datatype="string" friendlyname="LH heading 2">{CMS_CONTENT3}</content3>        <content4 datatype="text" friendlyname="LH box 2">{CMS_CONTENT4}</content4>        <content5 datatype="text" friendlyname="Main content">{CMS_CONTENT5}</content5>        <content6 datatype="string" friendlyname="RH heading 2">{CMS_CONTENT6}</content6>        <content7 datatype="text" friendlyname="RH box 2">{CMS_CONTENT7}</content7></content></doc>